Now that we've focused on the order of things and how we use those numbers in sequence we can now talk
现在我们已经专注于事物的顺序以及我们如何按顺序使用这些数字，我们现在可以谈谈
about dates and dates are actually written many different ways.
关于日期和日期实际上有很多不同的写法。
But the standard format for America OK.
但是美国的标准格式还可以。
So I'm an American teacher I can teach you the standard format in the US.
所以我是一名美国老师，我可以教你美国的标准格式。
You'll often see on an internet forum you'll see m m d d y y y y like that.
你会经常在一个互联网论坛上看到你会看到这样的 m d d y y y y。
So month day year you're at the full year and only the for the month.
所以月日年你是全年，只有一个月。
You write two numbers and for the day you write two numbers like that in that order.
你写了两个数字，并且在当天你按那个顺序写了两个数字。
So what would this be if we were going to write it before we say it let's write it.
那么，如果我们在说让我们写它之前先写它，那会是什么。
Well m m would be 0 7 0 7.
那么 mm 将是 0 7 0 7。
D D would be 15 and Y Y Y would be two thousand seventeen.
D D 是 15 岁，Y Y Y 是两千一十七岁。
Can we say 2017.
我们可以说2017年。
Yes.
是的。
So four years if it's well we'll talk about these years but if it's in this century the century we're
所以四年，如果情况好的话，我们会谈论这些年，但如果是在这个世纪，我们就是这个世纪
in we say for example this one we say two thousand seventeen two thousand.
例如，在我们说这个时，我们说 2,172,000。
We also say twenty seventeen.
我们也说二十七。
2017.
2017 年。
Now that's usually only four teens back when it was for example this most people would say two thousand
现在通常只有四个十几岁，例如大多数人会说两千
five instead of 20 0 5.
5 而不是 20 0 5。
You could say 20 0 5.
你可以说 20 0 5。
But most people will say 2005 2001 2009.
但大多数人会说 2005 2001 2009。
You don't have to put end in there either.
你也不必在那里结束。
You don't have to.
你不必。
OK.
好的。
And we'll talk about then this as well and this so that it's comfortable to say years even if it's a
然后我们也会讨论这个和这个，这样可以很舒服地说几年，即使它是一个
long time ago.
很久以前。
Now this one would be August August.
现在这个将是八月八月。
This is the abbreviation for August a Yuji.
这是August a Yuji的缩写。
If we want to write it out and then even though we don't have the R D here usually when we say it will
如果我们想把它写出来然后即使我们这里没有 R D 通常当我们说它会
imagine there is an R D here so we'll say August 3rd 1773 1773.
假设这里有一个 R D，所以我们会说 1773 年 8 月 3 日 1773 年。
So it's like saying 2017 1773.
所以这就像说 2017 1773。
We would not say one thousand seven hundred seventy three.
我们不会说一千七百七十三。
No we would not say usually.
不，我们通常不会说。
Seventeen hundred seventy three.
一千七百七十三。
Usually not.
通常不会。
Yeah.
是的。
Could you could but usually not.
你可以，但通常不会。
We can say it here.
我们可以在这里说。
If it's an even one.
如果是偶数。
But otherwise we don't.
但否则我们不会。
So for example this one would be DC which is the abbreviation of December December.
因此，例如，这将是 DC，它是 December December 的缩写。
This one we imagine a little s t here because there's a one December thirty first and then for this
我们在这里稍微想象一下，因为有一个 12 月 30 日，然后是这个
we say we say let me make a little space down here we say nineteen hundred nineteen hundred eighteen
我们说我们说让我在这里腾出一点空间我们说一千九百一千八十八
hundred seventeen hundred sixteen hundred.
一千七百一千六百。
If it's this though 1 9 0 2 then we would say 19 0 2 19 0 2 we would use 0 0 2 19 0 2 19 0 3 1913.
如果是这样，虽然 1 9 0 2 那么我们会说 19 0 2 19 0 2 我们会使用 0 0 2 19 0 2 19 0 3 1913。
OK so December 30 first nineteen hundred.
好的，所以 12 月 30 日前 1900 日。
August 3rd 1773 July 15th 2017 and again if we were going to write this how would we write it in America
1773 年 8 月 3 日 2017 年 7 月 15 日，如果我们要写这个，我们将如何在美国写它
we would write m m twelve D D thirty one y y y y nineteen hundred and 1 9 0 0.
我们会写 m m 12 D D 31 y y y 1900 1 9 0 0。
That's how we'd write it but because it's long ago in history it will probably be written this way it
这就是我们写它的方式，但因为它在历史上很久以前，它可能会这样写
probably will be written like that if you read it in a book it's probably written like this because
如果您在一本书中阅读它可能会这样写，它可能会这样写，因为
it's something that happened a long time ago.
这是很久以前发生的事情。
We usually write today's date on a Doctors form or something like that we'll write that in this format
我们通常将今天的日期写在医生表格或类似的东西上，我们会以这种格式写
or if we're filling out a filling out a form filling out a form or an application perhaps an application
或者，如果我们正在填写表格，填写表格或申请，也许是申请
online then we'll use this format usually and not every country is the same.
在线，那么我们通常会使用这种格式，并不是每个国家都是一样的。
And sometimes you will see it written in other ways you might see sometimes you might actually see the
有时您会看到它以您可能会看到的其他方式编写，有时您可能实际上会看到
R D there you may you may sometimes you'll see three August 1773 sometimes with no comma that's there
研发在那里你可能有时你会看到三个 August 1773 有时没有逗号
sometimes not in America usually you'll see d d m m y y y.
有时不在美国，通常你会看到 d d m m y y y。
Different countries are different and there are a lot of different ways to do it but I'm trying to give
不同的国家是不同的，有很多不同的方法可以做到，但我试图给出
you a feeling for how it's typically typically done.
你对它通常是如何完成的感觉。
For example let's say the date is let's say it's 10 20 2 1 9 9 3.
例如，假设日期是 10 20 2 1 9 9 3。
OK so how would we say that I want you to say that to yourself right now if you said Tobar twenty second
好吧，如果你说 Tobar 二十秒，我们该怎么说我想让你现在对自己说
nineteen ninety three.
一九九三年。
You are correct.
你是对的。
October 10 twenty second.
10 月 10 日二十二日。
Add a little end either.
也可以加一点结尾。
Nineteen ninety three.
一九九三年。
You're right.
你是对的。
Now sometimes dates don't quite fit into the very simple category of one day.
现在有时日期不太适合非常简单的一天类别。
But there's actually a a range a range of dates.
但实际上有一个日期范围。
Now how would we say that if we have a if we have a range of dates that means it begins here and and
现在我们怎么说，如果我们有一个如果我们有一个日期范围，这意味着它从这里开始，并且
could be all the way over here or anything in between.
可能一直在这里或介于两者之间。
Well what do you mean by that.
那你是什么意思。
Well I'll give you an example of an American holiday called Thanksgiving.
好吧，我给你举个例子，一个叫做感恩节的美国节日。
It's a harvest celebration.
这是一个丰收庆典。
We're celebrating our thankfulness to our family members that we have them around and our friends.
我们正在庆祝我们感谢我们的家人和我们的朋友。
We eat a lot of food.
我们吃很多食物。
It's it's anyway it's an American celebration.
无论如何，这是美国的庆祝活动。
It's the fourth Thursday in November.
这是十一月的第四个星期四。
That's when it's held.
那是它举行的时候。
So that's not always on the same day is it.
所以这并不总是在同一天是吧。
Sometimes that might be the twenty sixth sometimes the 25th.
有时可能是第 26 次，有时是第 25 次。
So how can we say that.
那我们怎么能这么说。
Well we could say Thanksgiving is on the fourth Thursday in November.
好吧，我们可以说感恩节是在十一月的第四个星期四。
The abbreviation of November is by the way.
顺便说一句，十一月的缩写。
And O V.
和 O V。
And the fourth Thursday in November and usually falls falls.
十一月的第四个星期四，通常是秋天。
Yes.
是的。
It's like it sort of landed there and usually falls between the twenty sixth and twenty eighth of the
就好像它降落在那里，通常落在
month usually falls between the twenty sixth and the twenty eighth of the month.
月份通常在该月的第 26 号和第 28 号之间。
What month.
什么月份。
November November.
十一月十一月。
Because I already said November I shouldn't say November twice.
因为我已经说过十一月，所以我不应该说十一月两次。
I can just say the month.
我只能说月份。
So that's how you would say different years.
这就是你所说的不同年份的方式。
That's how you say the months and the days on those years and how you often see them written and that
这就是你所说的那些年的月份和日子，以及你经常看到它们写成的样子
is how you describe a range when a certain date might be within a certain period of time.
当某个日期可能在某个时间段内时，您如何描述一个范围。
So I hope that's clear.
所以我希望这很清楚。
Now let's move on and talk about symbols.
现在让我们继续讨论符号。
We're going to talk about symbols next.
接下来我们将讨论符号。